staples.com.au 2014-11-21

# Office Supplies, Ink & Toner, Copy Paper, Technology & Electronics - Welcome to Staples.com.au

[Home](http://www.staples.com.au/) » [Policies](http://www.staples.com.au/wrapper.aspx?param=help_policie) » Privacy Ploicy

At Staples we value the trust of our customers. To earn your trust, we respect your privacy in handling personal information relating to you and your transactions with us. 

Our Privacy Policy explains the types of information we collect, how and why we collect information and how you may access and update personal information. This policy and the Privacy Act does not apply to employee records held by Staples.

## What we collect

We collect the following personal information: 

  * Customer name, address, contact details (including phone, fax and email) and trade references
  * Names and addresses of the directors, proprietors and owners of corporate customers and any personal guarantors, which are collected as a part of our credit application processes
  * Credit card details
  * Date of birth details for customers who order alcohol from us

Ancillary to our core business activities, we also collect and maintain records of personal information. For example:

  * Contractor name, address, licence, contact and emergency contact details which are used for the purposes of managing our various contractors in accordance with the requirements of our customers and our business requirements; and
  * Potential employee resumes and contact details which are used as a part of the recruitment process for new employees. 

## How we use and collect personal information

The personal information is collected for the purposes of fulfilling your requests for products and services, performing the necessary credit checks in accordance with our credit application processes, marketing our goods and services (including direct marketing) and receiving payment. Staples may collect your personal information directly from you, when you place an order, where you access and interact with the website or with the Staples Customer Service or Credit team. Staples may also collect information about you that is publicly available including information from websites such as LinkedIn or other websites. There may be occasions when Staples collects personal information from a third party. For example, Staples may also collect personal information from credit reporting bodies and sales and marketing organisations such as Dunn & Bradstreet.

We are required by Liquor Licensing laws to obtain your date of birth if and when you order alcohol from us. We use this information solely for the purposes of complying with our legal obligations, and in order to ensure alcohol is not sold to anyone under the age of 18.

## Who has access to personal information

Related body corporates of Staples and contractors may have access to and use your personal information. Personal information may from time to time be retained on data storage systems owned and operated by these related body corporates or contractors in overseas locations in which Staples' related body corporates or contractors operate. 

The countries in which such recipients are likely to be located are available [here](http://www.staples.co.uk/Wrapper.aspx?param=international).

## What about cookies

Cookies are small data files that are stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies do not give us control over your computer.

Our websites utilise "cookies" to provide you with a more convenient shopping experience, such as remembering your login name and password, purchase history and maintaining items in your shopping cart if you leave the site before checkout. 

## Marketing

Personal information is used by Staples for its legitimate business purposes, as disclosed at the time of collection. It is also used for ancillary purposes such as locating and identifying you and for servicing our relationship with you. Your contact details may also be used by us for the purposes of sending marketing correspondence to you. You may make a request to us not to receive direct marketing communications.

Staples undertakes not to sell, rent or trade personal information. We will not disclose personal information to third parties for them to market goods and services to you. We will not otherwise use or disclose your personal information unless the use or disclosure is authorised under the Australian Privacy Principles. Some examples of where use or disclosure is authorised under the Australian Privacy Principles are:

  * Use or disclosure is required or authorised by or under law
  * Use or disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life, health or safety
  * Use or disclosure is necessary to investigate suspected unlawful activity, to prevent or detect a criminal offence or seriously improper conduct
  * Use or disclosure is reasonably necessary for the conduct of or preparation for court proceedings; or
  * You have consented, either expressly or impliedly, to our disclosing the information about you. 

As with most business organisations, Staples relies on third party suppliers (agents) to conduct specialised activities such as mail-outs and the dispatch of internet messages. These agents act on behalf of Staples and do not facilitate their own commerical agendas whilst processing your personal information. While personal information may be provided to these agents to enable them to perform their agreed tasks, such information remains the property of Staples at all times and the agent organisations involved may not use or disclose it for their own purposes. To "opt-out" of receiving marketing materials email us at [marketing@staples.com.au](mailto:marketing@staples.com.au).

## How to update your Personal Information and have access to it

We seek to keep personal information that is accurate, complete and up-to-date. To assist us with this, please contact us if any of the details you have provided change. Further, if you believe that the information we have about you is not accurate, complete or up-to-date, contact us and we will correct it.

On request we will provide you with access to the personal information we store about you, but only to the extent we are able by law, and are required under the Australian Privacy Principles.

If we are unable to give you the access requested, we will, if reasonable, consider whether the use of an intermediary would allow sufficient access to meet both our needs. We will also provide you with the reasons for our inability to give you the access requested.

## How secure is the data collected

Staples is committed to keep secure the data you provide us and we will take all reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or unauthorised access or alteration.

## Changes to This Policy

Staples may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. This Privacy Policy was last amended on 7 March 2014.

## Contact Us About Privacy

If you would like further information regarding this Privacy Policy or if you believe that the privacy of your personal information has been compromised, please contact the Privacy Officer by email at [privacy@staples.com.au](mailto:privacy@staples.com.au), or in writing to:

The Privacy Officer  
Staples Australia Pty Limited  
163 O'Riordan Street  
Mascot NSW 2020

Should you not be satisfied with the outcome, you may contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.
